Here's another example.
This is cryptarithmetic.
How many of you have solved
a cryptarithmetic problem?
OK.
Very important for things such
as robotic crime fighting.
In a cryptarithmetic problem, the
variables are the letters in the
arithmetic problem, and each
letter stands for a number.
So here, the variables are things
like the F, the T, and so on.
There's some extra variables
you need to insert--
X1, X2, X3 for the carry bits.
When you actually solve this, you need
to keep track of whether or not you
carried a one.
Each of these variables has a single
digit domain, so 0 to 9.
And the constraints indicate, well, when
you substitute something in for O
and something in for R, then O plus
O has to equal R, and so on.
And so if we wrote this out, we would
write things like, well, they all have
to be different, and O plus O equals R,
and we would connect in the carry
bit and so on.
We're not going to go through the
details of cryptarithmetic, but the
point here is, these constraints aren't
that complicated to phrase, but
they actually touch more than
two variables at once.
And so what we can do is we can draw the
constraint graph here, but we'll
find out that an arc doesn't suffice.
So for example, for this constraint
here, this one touches O, R, and X1,
and that's this constraint right here.
And when we have constraint graphs that
contain constraints that are more
them binary, meaning they touch more
than two variables, we draw them as a
square to indicate the constraints, and
we connect that square up to all
of the variables that are constrained.
Here's another example.
Sudoku.
How many people have played Sudoku?
OK.
So, here's an example of Sudoku.
The variables here, every open
square takes on some value.
So it's going to be a variable.
The domains are going to
be one through nine.
That's how Sudoku works.
And there are constraints.
What do the constraints look like?
Well, every column has to have nine
different values, and every row has to
have nine different values.
Every three by three square as shown has
to have nine different values in
that region.
And we could just encode these all
different things as a bunch of
pairwise inequality constraints,
that would be fine too.
But you get the idea of how a Sudoku
board can be phrase as an
instance of a CSP.
OK, we've seen a bunch of examples of
CSPs so far that look very much like
puzzles, kind of configurational
things.
Here's an example of a CSP that does
something very, very different.
So this is the Waltz Algorithm.
The Waltz Algorithm was originally
designed for interpreting line
drawings of solid polyhedra
in three dimensions.
So for example, you would have some
robot looking at some scene, and it
would see some line drawing that it got
out of a vision system, and it's
trying to figure out what
the heck is this thing.
Is it concave?
Is it convex?
Is it what kind of structure?
You can think of this, I mean, unless
you've got Escher drawing your
structures here, that when you look at
these, you'd see, OK, that vertex
there is an outie, right?
It's pointing out at you.
And this one here, this
one's in innie.
But they kind of both look
the same locally.
They both have three lines
coming together.
And in order to be able to look at a
drawing like this and figure out which
of the corners are innies and which of
them are outies, the Waltz Algorithm
was developed.
This is an early example of a
computation that you'd want to do
posed as a declarative constraint
satisfaction problem.
So what's the approach?
The approach is that each intersection
is a variable.
So for example, you'd have
a variable here.
You'd have another variable here.
And adjacent intersections impose
constraints on each other.
Like, if the top one is an outie, the
bottom one can't be an innie in this
particular case, in a certain way.
If you then solved the CSP, all of
the physically realizable 3D
interpretations show up as solutions
of the constraint
satisfaction problem.
So here's a neat case where kind
of we've encoded a geometric
interpretation problem as a CSP.
Same machinery to solve
as the rest of them.